Muhammad Talha Qadir

<u>m.t alha.qadir779@gmail.com</u> | <u>contact@mtqadir.me</u> | +923070979731 <u>mtqadir.me</u> | <u>github.com/mtalhaqadir779</u>| <u>linkedin.com/in/talha-qadir</u>

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Programmer and Cyber Security enthusiast with some hands-on experience in Google Cloud Platform, Web development and deployment using HTML, CSS, jquery, Angular, and other frameworks. I am a hard working, honest individual. I am a good timekeeper, always willing to learn new skills. An enthusiastic, self-motivated, reliable, and responsible person. Having good problem solving skills and great to work with teams and easy to get along with.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Personal Portfolio Website (https://mtgadir.me)

March 2021-Present

- Designed and planned responsive Front-End Design for Website using Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- Deployed the Website on GitHub pages to add custom domain.
- Tested the website on different platforms for compatibility and responsiveness and deployed.

Volunteer at Chadar Foundation NUST

Sep 2020-Oct-2020

- Co-Managed the Sahara project in Bahawalpur.
- Assisted in collection, packing and distribution of donated clothes and other necessities to locals in need.
- Documented and reported the process to the Foundation.

Eco-Intern at WWF-Pakistan

July 2019-Aug 2019

- Handled Social media activities.
- Provided IT support to team.
- Developed team communications and information for meetings.

EDUCATION

School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences, NUST

Bachelor of Computer Sciences

2018-2022

Rangers College, Bahawalpur

Intermediate (Pre-Engineering), A+ Grades

2016-2018

PROJECTS

Customer Feedback Sentiment Analysis using LSTM Neural Network:

- Created a LSTM based RNN predicting the Sentiments from customers textual reviews.
- Cleaned and Preprocessed the US Airline Twitter Reviews Dataset and trained the model.
- Deployed the model using Flask Web Framework with an accuracy of 92 percent.

Web app to analyze Crop requirements (View Certificate):

- Guided Project of ML in Python with streamlit.
- Developed Web application to analyze soil conditions and recommend best farming practices accordingly.

Multi-Threaded Web Crawler (View Repository):

- Object Oriented Approach
- Used C++ pthreads to download html pages from the Web and parse the content for new links
- Mutex Locks to avoid deadlocks

Bus Ticketing Management System:

- Object Oriented Approach in C++
- Used Different Data Structures to Store retrieve and search ticketing data
- Console based System for Seat Reservations

Obstacle Car racing Game in Java(OOP):

- Object Oriented Approach
- Based on basic understanding of Object-oriented concepts
- Simple UI using Java.

Library Management System in C (View Repository):

- Provides hands on experience to all the basic programming and C language fundamentals.
- Made a Console based C application for Library management.
- Used file handling, reading, and writing algorithms and libraries to implement a structured management system.

CERIFICATES

Introduction to Cyber Security (View Certificate):

- Offered by Cisco Networking academy.
- Basic introduction to Network and Cyber Security

GCP Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure (View Certificate):

- Offered by Google Cloud at Couresra.org
- Introduction to GCP platform and their core infrastructure.

Web Design and Development (View Certificates):

- Offered by University of Michigan on Coursera.org
- Web design using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Web Application development using PHP, MySQL, NoSQL

SKILLS

- Familiar with Flutter framework and dart.
- Familiar with Google Cloud Platform
- Efficient in programming using Python and C/C++.
- Critical Thinking and Problem Solving
- Web Development using HTML5 CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL
- Configuring simple networks using software-based Cisco Network Tracer